Guide to the Mali Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Mali collection
1905-2008
1959-1996
MS 1529
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.27
(7 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to cultural, political, economic, and social conditions in Mali.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically, with photographs last. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to cultural, political, economic, and social conditions in Mali.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Children -- Mali; Women -- Mali; Mali -- Economic conditions; Mali -- Politics and government; Union démocratique du peuple malien
- Original Accession
  - Government journals; newsletters; printed material; speeches, 1959-1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Periodicals, 1960-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Political organizations: journals; newsletters; printed material, 1981-1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Kalimu, Bulletin de Liaison": Union des Ecrivains Maliens, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Union Démocratique du Peuple Malien (UDPM): printed material, 1986-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, Accession 1995-M-150
  - Additional printed materials, 1988-1996, undated (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 2000-M-026
  - Additional printed materials, [196-], [1982?], 1994-1996 (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession 2006-M-019
  - Ambassade de France Service de Presse et d'Information
    - Community Affairs, nos. 9, 13, 1959 Dec, 1960 June (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "U.N. Security Council Votes to Recommend the Admission of the Mali Federation to the United Nations" [address by Ambassador Armand Berard, Permanent Representative of France to the United Nations], 1960 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jekabaara Jamana: Cikela ceman n'a musoman kunnafoniseben, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Le Petit Journal: Supplément Illustré, no. 772, 1905 September 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sadogo, Klena. "Oral Tradition and Archaeology," Institut des Sciences Humaines, Bamako, Circa 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Saheli [Sahélienne Edition newspaper, no. 5], 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Seydou Keita, Photographer: Portraits from Bamako, Mali"[program for exhibit at the National Museum of African Art, Smithsonian Institution, 1996 Mar 27-Jul 28] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional Material, 1971-2005; Accession 2010-M-074; Materials are arranged as received.
  - Manuscripts of Timbuktu postcard, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Le Manuel du Citoyen, Dr. Abdoulaye Sall, 2004 March (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Djé, no. 1, Front Démocratique des Patriotes Maliens (F.D.P.M.), 1983 November (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Shinintle, bulletin no. 2, Comité de Défense des Libertés Démocratiques au Mali, 1984 March-April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Situation de l'Education des Filles dans les Pays du Sahel Causes et Perspectives," Adama Samassekou, Ministre de l'Education, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - L'Informateur, no. 28, 1971 April (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Musée National du Mali, guide, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Centre Djoliba: Recherche-Formation pour le Développement", 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mali, Invitation au voyage, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Règlement Intérieur," Association pour la Promotion Economique de la Femme (A.P.E.F.), 2003 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Statuts," AP.E.F., 2003 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - L'InfoDjoliba, no. 38, 1994 July (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Timbuktu Education Foundation (TEF) flyer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Center Djoliba: 40 ans au service du développement de Tout L'Homme et de Tous les hommes et femmes, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - GWA La Cuisine, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Institut du Sahel (INSAH), Indicateurs démographiques et socio-économiques du Mali, chart, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Frères d' Armes: Revue trimestrielle des Forces Armées et de Sécurité, no. 2, 1992 February 15-May 15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Timbuktu: The Untold Story, movie poster, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mali/CPS/Ministère de la Santé, demographic chart, 2002 July (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional material, 1976-2008, undated; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1976-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Posters, 2004, undated (Folder 2)